the elders and no man could learn that
song but the hundred and forty and four
thousand which were redeemed from the
earth I don't know if you realize what
you're looking at here but you are
looking at the end of a refugee March
right there in Revelation chapter 14
there will be at the end of this all a
group of people who stand on Mount Zion
Amen but that group of people looks
pretty small a hundred and forty-four
thousand I don't want to get into right
now whether this number is symbolic or
literal but let me let you know that the
number is small compared to those who
started out on the journey because the
Bible says that God is not willing that
any should perish but that all should
come to repentance that all should have
eternal life
and so revelation 14 is the end of a
refugee journey because the Bible tells
us that we are actually refugees did you
know that it tells us that we are
strangers that we are pilgrims in a land
in a strange land and so as I look at
revelation 14 I say to myself man I want
to make I want to complete that march to
Zion that is the title of the message
today the march to Zion just by show of
hands how many of you want to make that
March how many of you realize that you
have an adversary an enemy who is doing
everything in its power to eliminate you
so that you will not get to Mount Zion
Satan would like to do everything in his
power to stop us from experiencing that
Mount Zion experience let me share with
you that those verses in Revelation
chapter 14 represent an experienced
Mount
represents an experience once again how
many of you want to experience Mount
Zion very good what I want to share with
you today is really the story of our
journey to Mount Zion we are marching to
where everyone Ziya we're what we're
hoping for that Mount Zion experience
but I'm going to share with you that in
order to get that Mount Zion experience
in order to accomplish that Mount Zion
experience there are other experiences
that we must have in order to get to
Mount Zion and so what we're going to do
today is we're going to look at six
mountains in the Bible that in essence
reveal to us the Christian experience
and what it takes for us to end up on
Mount Zion we're going to be looking at
these mountains in order the first
mountain is Mount Ararat after that
we're going to be looking at Mount
Moriah
after that we're going to be looking at
Mount Sinai after that we're gonna be
looking at Mount Carmel and then we're
gonna look at the Mount of Olives and
then we're going to complete it with the
Mount with Mount Zion
so in all there are six mountains how
many mountains every one six mountains
now if Mount Zion represents an
experience then it would be safe for us
to conclude that these other mountains
also represent what experiences
experiences that we must have in order
to make it to Mount Zion let's begin
with Mount Ararat I want you to turn
with me to the book of Genesis chapter
six
Genesis chapter six in Genesis chapter
six beginning with verse 1 the Bible
says and it came to pass when men began
to multiply on the face of the earth and
daughters were born on to them that the
sons of God saw the daughters of
men that they were fair and they took
them wives all of which they chose and
the Lord said my spirit shall not always
strive with man for that he is also
flesh yet his days shall be an hundred
and twenty years verse five and God saw
the wickedness of man was great in the
earth and that every imagination of the
thoughts of his heart was only evil
continually you all know this story
correct this is the story of the flood
and in this story of the flood what we
find is that sin has been so embraced
that it leads God to destroy the world
God calls a man by the name of Noah and
he tells Noah to build an an arc and
that arc we will find in Genesis chapter
8 eventually takes Noah and those who
are saved in the ark with him come with
me to Genesis chapter 8 verse 1 the
Bible says and God remembered Noah and
every living thing and all the cattle
that was with him in the ark and God
made a wind to pass over the earth and
the waters are saged the Fountains also
the deep and the windows of heaven were
stopped and the rain from heaven was
restrained and the waters returned from
off the earth from off the earth
continually and after the end of the
hundred and fifty days the water of Adan
and the ark rested in the seventh month
on the seventeenth day of the month upon
the mountains of Ararat if you and I
were to take a trip to Mount Ararat and
ask ourselves what does this experience
what does this mountain tell us here's
what the mountain tells us the mountain
tells us that sin wrecks everything did
you catch that as we stand upon Mount
Ararat
we look out and we remember we remember
I'm talking about
spiritual journey of the mount ararat we
look at me see whoa the result of sin is
that it wrecks everything how many of
you can attest to that how many of you
remember your life before you came to
Christ was it a self-destructive life
was it a life that kind of like maybe
everything you touch it just ended up
not so good how many of you remember
your Ararat days where it was just like
chaos Mount Ararat reminds us that sin
wrecks everything in James chapter 1
verse 14 the Bible says but every man is
tempted when he is drawn away of his own
lust lust and enticed
then when must have conceived it
bringeth forth sin and sin when it is
finished bringeth forth death Mount
Ararat reminds us that the wages of sin
is death but I want you to notice
something you see Mount Ararat was a
transition point for everyone because
Mount Ararat remember the Mount Ararat
experience is actually necessary in
order to get to Mount Zion because
remember it was there in this story that
God commands Noah to build an ark and so
here you have two groups of people who
are faced with a choice either they can
embrace sin and love it so much that
they will be destroyed or they can
embrace the way out that God has
provided for them in this Ark that was
built and let me tell you most of the
world embraced what sin and as a result
guess what happened they were eliminated
from the march all right if you get that
what I just said just now doesn't mean
here let me hear you say Amen Mount
Ararat symbolizes the fact that sin
destroys everything God says listen I'm
gonna give you guys a chance because I
want you to make it through this Mount
rat experience and the way you make it
through this mount ararat experience is
that you accept what I have given to you
which is the ark you can either accept
that or you can cling to sin and and
what the Bible is letting us know here
is that those who cling to sin are
eliminated from the march how many of
you want to keep marching yeah listen
it's it's it's actually it's a powerful
message God saves us out of our messes
God provides a way of salvation God
provided that ark to save whosoever
would get on it but most people decided
they want to cling to sin and as a
result they are eliminated but here's
some good news you see you may still be
rejecting God's will for your life I may
still be clinging to sin but you know
what God never gives up on you he never
gives up on you you could get up every
day saying I reject the Ark I reject the
Ark I reject the art which by the way is
a type of Jesus Christ
I reject a path of salvation and every
day God comes back at you because the
Bible says he's not willing that any
should perish so you may have died
spiritually speaking a thousand times
over in your era bad experience because
you are choosing sin over God but God is
always there to give you another chance
to accept him as long as you have breath
praise God most of you are here right
now because guess what you made it
through your ararat experience
you chose the ark over sin that's why
you're here today you you you had your
Ararat experience and praise God for it
but listen to me you can't just stay on
Mount Ararat you can't just say hey you
know what I gave up my old ways
oh habits and that's good enough no no
you have to keep moving because the idea
is we are marching to Zion see Mount
Ararat and turning away from your always
is what prepares you for the next
experience which is the Mount Moriah
experience come with me in Genesis
Genesis chapter 22 in Genesis chapter 22
we read the story of a man by the name
of Abraham and the Bible says in verse 1
it came to pass after these things that
God did tempt Abraham and said unto Him
Abraham and he said Behold here am I and
he said take now thy son thine only son
Isaac whom thou lovest and get thee into
the land of Moriah and offer him there
for a burnt offering upon one of the
mountains which I shall tell thee of how
many of you remember this story
and Abraham it's here being called to
sacrifice his beloved son Isaac is
Abraham faced with a choice here what is
God calling Abraham to do
he's calling him to lay everything on
the altar remember Isaac is really a
type of who Jesus Christ who himself
laid everything on the altar for us the
Mount Moriah experience points us to the
sacrifice of Jesus Christ and remember
Jesus said listen if you will follow
after me you have to give up everything
to follow me so look just as at Mount
Ararat there were those who chose to
cling to sin and those who chose to
accept the ark so at Mount Moriah there
are those who will say yes Lord
eiders I will give everything up for you
and those who are like ah you know what
I think you're asking a little bit too
much I mean if you remember that rich
young ruler
what master what good thing must I do to
have eternal life and Jesus says send
all that you have and do what follow me
and the Bible says this rich young ruler
turned away sad because he had great
possessions it's not that he was anti
God it's not like he was those on who or
who in the mount ararat experience were
like no we choose sin rather than God no
he wanted to follow God many of us
really right you know Lord I really
really really want to follow you but
there's just some things that I think
you're asking too much I'm beloved just
just as we can make a choice to reject
the ark so we can make a choice to
refuse to give all for Jesus Christ and
beloved let me tell you that they are
many there are many who perish at Mount
Moriah because they hear God say I want
you to lay this on the altar for me and
they're like lay what on the altar nah
I'm not can you imagine if Abraham said
no to God where would we be right now
right so many are perishing saying no
God I'm not giving that up but guess
what there's good news because even
though you may be getting up every day
of your life and saying to God no that's
too much that's too much God is not
willing that any should perish and he
comes at you every day with the
sacrifice of himself saying listen I'm
still here for you if you would just lay
all down for me I will get you to Mount
Zion but I need you to trust with me
trust me I need you to walk with me I
need you to obey me I need you to leave
all down I need you to be willing to
give all up for me because I gave all up
for you now beloved let me say something
it is most likely that you're here right
now because you accepted Christ at Mount
Moriah
with me it's most likely that you're
here right now because yes you you you
have that Ararat experience where you
say you know what I choose God rather
than the world and then that prepared
you with mama riders say yes you know
what I'm willing to lay down all for
Jesus Christ so that I can follow him
and listen you can do that and that is
excellent but you can't just camp out at
a Mount Moriah experience why because
we're marching where we marching to Zion
you see the Mount Moriah experience is
what prepares you for the next
experience which is Mount Sinai come
with me to the book of Exodus you see
you'll remember that there in the book
of Exodus Exodus chapter 20 we find
Moses and the children of Israel at the
Mount where they receive something what
do they receive they received the law of
God listen to me carefully at Mount
Sinai God reveals that he has a people
and that people received the law of God
not only do they receive the law of God
in Exodus chapter 20 but an Exodus
chapter 25 they are given the sanctuary
there's got to wait for you to think and
meditate on that they are given the
sanctuary message okay
at Mount Sinai God cause of people gives
them the commandments he also gives them
the sanctuary message and on that same
mountain you'll remember in Exodus 32
where the Bible says that the children
of Israel began to say let's go back to
we're back to Egypt and while they're
doing this and while they decide they're
going to go worship a golden calf
the Bible says Moses came down from the
mountain and then he makes his call who
is on the Lord's side let him come out
so there's an apostasy that is going on
and then there is a group of people that
come out who was that group of people
the Levites and as a result of them
coming out of the apostasy God gives
them the priesthood okay so wait let's
go back then I'm Mount Sinai God calls
the people no no no let's do this at
Mount Ararat it tells us about the
introduction of sin and the results of
clinging to sin are you with me and
those who who claim to sin are destroyed
while the rest get to do what get to
move on keep marching we then get to
Mount Moriah which points us to the
sacrifice of who of Jesus Christ right
and those who accept the sacrifice of
Jesus Christ remember Isaac was to be
the seed which would produce a great
Rock's multitude wow that reminds me of
Jesus Christ who died for us in the New
Testament but after Mount Moriah you not
have Mount Sinai in which God calls a
people into existence if you will after
coming out of slavery who have three
things they have the law they have the
sanctuary and they have the priesthood
they have the law they have the
sanctuary and they have does that remind
you of any people on this earth today
Church you see a Mount Sinai God says
this listen because you turned your back
on sin I remember I turn my back on sin
I remember the world that I lived in and
and the fame that was offered me and I
remember that mount ararat experience
while I was like whoa this I gotta give
this up because I want to follow God and
then I remember my mom my mom Mariah
experience which was listen do you
accept Jesus are you willing to lay all
down for him and after I accepted that
guess what happened God's analysis me I
want to let you know that I have a
people on this planet and those people
are called seventh-day adventists they
have the law they have the sanctuary
message and I've called them to be my
priest oh whoa Wow so I'm not sorry I
God is saying to us listen don't be
deceived don't be fooled I've called you
out of darkness and I'm letting you know
that I have a people with a mission and
endtime mission you see beloved remember
that it was at Mount Sinai that some
people said we want to go back to Egypt
listen to me you you you know that
because you may be here now but you have
friends and former brothers and sisters
who looked back to Egypt and said man
you know what I missed the record deal I
missed the drinking I'm mister hanging
out with the old friends and doing
things the hallway and so even at Mount
Sinai there is an option you can either
choose to continue on marching with God
or you can choose to do what go back to
Egypt which will you choose you see
beloved those who chose to go back to
Egypt were eliminated from the March
while those who said I am on the Lord's
side they continued on on
but guess what God is merciful because
even for those who have turned back to
Egypt you know what God is doing he is
still there day after day saying listen
you can come back to me you can come
back to me I know you turned from eat I
know you've turned from your from
following me and I know that you you
have chosen Egypt over me but I'm
telling you that I am not willing that
any should perish I want to get as many
people to Mount Zion as is possible
so day by day day after day he's there
with extended arms saying will you come
back to me he's sleeping over the law of
God is really a transcript of the
character of Jesus Christ the sanctuary
is really pointing to who Jesus Christ
is
and the priesthood is really telling us
that Christ is our heavenly high priest
who is interceding on our behalf in
other words beloved on every mountain
the reason we get to move forward is
because of one the arc to the sacrifice
of Isaac 3 the character of Christ in in
his law in the sanctuary and in the
priesthood it's all Jesus Christ that
helps us to move forward at every step
of the journey this refugee journey we
are on it is Jesus Christ that is there
with us at every step of the way trying
to help us to advance to the next
mountain beloved it's not good enough
for us to just camp out at Mount Sinai
is it because Mount Sinai is designed to
help us prepare for what's coming next
you know what's coming next
it's mile Carmel I don't know if you you
caught that just now it's Mount Carmel
you know what happens at Mount Carmel
see a Mount Carmel there's this woman by
the name of Jezebel and she's married to
a half and the two of them together it's
interesting they represent kind of like
this church and state power that seeks
to persecute the people of God and so
what I want you to understand beloved is
that our mark our Mount Carmel is coming
it's not it's actually here and in order
for us to be ready for Mount Carmel we
have to have experienced Mount Ararat
the turning away of sin we had to
experience Mount Moriah the accepting of
Christ and being willing to lay all that
on the altar for him we've had to
experience Mount Sinai meaning yes God
has a people and I know who those people
are because they're the people who keep
the commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus and understand the
sanctuary message and know what their
high priest is doing in heaven because
that is what prepares us to not make the
fatal mistake that occurred at Mount
Carmel because you remember at Mount
Carmel that there's a man by the name of
Elijah and Elijah calls all the people
together and listen beloved here's what
he says to them he calls them together
he says how long hard you between two
opinions and the Bible says if God be
God serve him but if not if bailed and
serve him and the Bible says the people
answered him not a word hold on how did
they get to the place where they
answered him not a word how do
Adventists get to the place where when
God's name and character is on the line
we stand there indifferently
we're here because evidently we we made
it through Ararat and we made it through
Mount Moriah and we made it through
Sinai but how
that had Mount Carmel which is where we
are right now how is it that we have
many people not answering a word being
indifferent let me share with you you
see the the the reason that the
Israelites got to where they were after
God had done so much for them it's
really very interesting see at this time
the truth of Israel are broken up into
two kingdoms you know those two kingdoms
were Judah and Israel and the Bible
tells us that Jeroboam was the king of
Israel and reborn was the king of Judah
and the reason that that happened is
because under David he United the
kingdom then under Solomon there was a
reign of peace but then solomon began to
apostatize towards the end of his life
and as a result of that god said i'm
gonna rent the kingdom from you and so
the kingdom became divided into two
Jeroboam having the twelve and Rael bomb
having the two twelve tribes and two and
the twelve tribes were now called Israel
and I want you to notice something I'm
just going to read to you about all the
kings of Israel by the way the kings of
Israel were they good or were they evil
evil how many kings did Israel have they
had about nineteen kings covering a span
of about two hundred years and those 19
kings every single one of them was
wicked now here's a question how in the
world can 19 kings straight just
straight continuously be wicked and you
want to know how listen I want you to
check this out tell me what these kings
all have in common I'm gonna read this
rapidly but I just want you to listen
several verses here
first Kings 15 26 and he did evil in the
sight of the Lord and walked in the way
of his father
his sin where would he made Israel to
sin for his sins which he sinned in
doing evil in the sight of the Lord and
walking in the way of Jeroboam and his
sin which he did to make Israel to sin
first King 16:30 and they had the son of
Omri did evil in the sight of the Lord
above all that were above him before and
it came to pass as it had been a light
thing for him to walk in the sins of
Jeroboam the son of Nebat
he took to wife Jezebel let me read on
first Kings 1625 but Omri wrought evil
in the eyes of the Lord and did worse
than all that were before him for he
walked in the way of Jeroboam son of
neither 2nd Kings chapter 10 verse 29
howbeit the sins of Jeroboam the son of
Nebat who made Israel to sin Jay who
departed not after them
2nd Kings chapter 10 verse 31 but Jay
who took no heed to walk in the law of
the Lord God with all his with all his
heart for he departed not from the sins
of Jeroboam second Kings 13 6
nevertheless they departed not from the
sins of the house of Jeroboam can you
see the constant thing here the sins of
who Jeroboam so here's a question what
were the sins of Jeroboam let me answer
you very quickly when Jeroboam got the
two the ten tribes and the house of
worship was in Judah Jeroboam said
listen I don't want to lose anyone in my
in my New Kingdom on your territory so
what I'm gonna do is I'm going to build
a new altar and a new place of worship
so that people will not go over there to
Judah because if they go there then I
might lose them so I'm gonna have them
worship right here
and so Jeroboam sets up what kind of
worship false worship and really beloved
false worship is simply an avenue
whereby you stop worshiping the God of
Israel so the Bible says that king after
king that arose continued in this path
of just simply listen carefully not
worshiping God
how is it that Israel gets to the place
where they are now like yeah God so what
it doesn't matter where they're in a
lukewarm state and condition it's
because they stopped worshipping God
they'd love it listen to me we have been
given a message as a church is that
right that message is found in
Revelation chapter 14 fear God and give
glory to him and worship Him who made
heaven the earth the scene of fountains
of water worship Him do what everyone
where what are we called to do as a
people worship every day we're to be
worshipping God not some days but every
day and what happens is this when when
Satan can set up stuff in our lives
idols so I'm not talking about cows like
Jeroboam setup but I'm talking about
anything your job your livelihood your
family your fun activities when Satan
can set something up in your life that
leads you simply listen carefully simply
leads you to just stop worshiping you
may still say I'm an Israelite you know
hey I I still believe in the God of
heaven but once he can get you to stop
worshiping what happens next is you end
up just like the children of Israel at
Mount Carmel answering not a word
lukewarm not realizing how far you have
fallen away from God so what does Elijah
do come on what does the lies are doing
this story he offers up a sacrifice
would you call that what's
doing he's worshiping Elijah's trying to
show listen the answer to your
lukewarmness if you want fire in your
life you've got to worship you can't
just sit back and say okay no no you
have to have fiery in life you have to
worship that's what the three angels
messages is all about it's about
worshipping God and so God says listen
for many of you at Mount Carmel you have
turned and worship other dogs you've
allowed other things to come into your
life where you're just not so really
caught up into God and the whole you
know yeah you believe in God and yeah
you may be in church but you know what
you're not really worshiping I'm beloved
that leads us to a very bad place
because you see what comes next is the
Mount of Olives and the Mount of Olives
in order for us to make it through the
Mount of Olives we must have been
prepared at Mount Carmel you see Mount
Carmel calls us to worship the true God
to stop haunting between two decisions
to stop being double-minded to stop
having one foot in the world and one
foot in the church that's what it's
calling us to do and those who choose to
straddle the fence will end up leaving
the journey because listen Mount of
Olives brings us into the New Testament
and you remember what happened in the
Mount of Olives correct
Jesus towards the end of his life he
when he has the last supper he the Bible
says they go out into the Mount of
Olives and there in the Mount of Olives
Jesus begins to go through his own
personal time of trouble because the
Bible says in Daniel 12:1 there is going
to be a time of trouble such as never
was and each one of us is going to have
a guest cemani experienced and beloved
listen to me if you have not
victoriously experienced our
if you have not been willing to give up
all at mount moriah if you have not been
willing to understand that God has a
people and a message and that people in
message is not Babylon it's not the
mysteries the fallen churches that God
has a true movement that he has called
his people into if you're not willing to
stand for God and not strand of a fence
when mount of all his hits you know what
you're gonna be found doing what was
Jesus doing what were his disciples
doing you know what you're gonna be film
doing you're gonna be found sleeping
you're gonna be found
unprepared you're gonna be found caught
off guard beloved Jesus becomes our
example a mount at the Mount of Olives
saying listen this is what you need to
do with me you need to worship because
that's what Christ was doing at the
Mount of Olives he was worshiping but in
order to worship God correctly you have
to have a successfully experienced Mount
Carmel you have to have it successfully
said listen I will not straddle the
fence
I will not halt between two opinions I
will serve the God of heaven Lord set me
on fire because it is that fire that is
needed and necessary so that when we get
to the Mount of Olives and it feels like
God is pulling away from you and you're
wondering why that you can have the
faith and the courage and the
determination and the experience listen
you're in the Mount of Olives aren't you
troubled yeah I'm troubled but you know
what I remember that God was with me on
my error
I remember that God was with me at Mount
Moriah
I remember my experience at Mount Sinai
I remember that God stood with me on
Mount Carmel so yes while the Mount of
Olives is difficult and I'm struggling I
know from past experience that God will
not forsake me
that God will not leave me alone that
God will walk through this with me he
will not leave me my beloved if you
don't have those experiences when we get
to the Mount of Olives when when the
enemies are on their way to persecute
the people of God like they were on
their way to persecute Jesus you are
going to like those disciples flee
Revelation chapter 7 we're closing Korky
you can prepare to come forward okay or
are you gonna pray there okay Revelation
chapter 7 revelation 7 tells us about a
group of people the Bible told says the
four angels of holding the four winds
back and then this group of people are
sealed they're described as the hundred
and forty and four thousand but right
after that the Bible says that John
looked and he saw a great what multitude
which no man could number and you know
what the Bible says about this great
multitude actually let me tell you the
great multitude the 144,000 is symbolic
of the great multitude so while we
thought that only 144,000 make it to
heaven no no no no beloved there is a
great multitude that makes it to heaven
now listen that great multitude is small
compared to the number of people that
were lost at Mount Ararat and Mount
Moriah and Mount Sinai and Mount Carmel
and Mount of Olives do you understand
what I'm saying but nonetheless it is a
great multitude that maked and when John
says who are these that are standing
before the throne the angel replies
these are they which came out of Great
Tribulation
as I look at those mountains Mount
Ararat Great Tribulation yeah Mount
Moriah Great Tribulation that Abraham
experienced great tribulation yeah
Mount Sinai was there Great Tribulation
was there a split in the campus people
of people saying we're turning back to
God we're turning back and going back to
Egypt and persuading everyone to go was
there Great Tribulation yes Mount Carmel
Great Tribulation yes Manav Allah's
Great Tribulation yes these are standing
on Mount Zion are standing there because
they have made it through Great
Tribulation beloved we are marching to
Zion and we've got to remember that in
order to get to Zion it is necessary for
us to go through these other mountains
but do not fear because God is with us
on every mountain he is walking with us
all the way so when the Bible says in
Revelation 14 I saw 144,000 stand with
the lamb it's not that vain the land
just met up on Mount Zion they and the
land have been together on every single
mountain God will walk with you at every
single step to assure that you make it
to salvation that you make it to Zion
the only thing you must do is cling to
him and not let go don't turn back don't
get discouraged this mountain is
difficult don't get discouraged keep
your eyes on Jesus and he will lead you
to Mount Zion